# Peterson Ribeiro dos Santos Zeferino

<u>petersonzeferino@gmail.com</u> <u>https://linkedin.com/in/petersonzeferino</u>

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

10+ years of total IT experience, working the most of this time with Development, Architecture, Testing and Usability Innovative and motivated self-starter experienced in different business segments such as Banking/Finance, Marketing, Health and Automotive

Involved in development of applications using:

- JavaScript, JQuery, Angular, React, Knockout
- C#, VB .NET, .NET Framework, .NET Core, Web API (REST), Webservice (WCF)
- SQL Server (Strong experience in creating and optimizing Stored Procedure, Functions and Triggers)
- Object Models and Class hierarchy for middleware deployment with .NET technologies
- · Agile Methodologies like SCRUM, SAFe and XP

Eager to learn and strong thirst for knowledge

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Senior Software Engineer**

May 2021 – Jun 2022

Cox Automotive

Cox Automotive is part of the large conglomerate of Cox Enterprises Inc. a global company that operates in the sale of vehicles through technological solutions, services and highly specialized staff that support consumers, manufacturers and dealers in all phases of the automotive experience

- Development of microservices using .NET for integrations with partners to financing, deliveries and auctions
- Code review, requirements analysis, design and architectural proposal for the development of new projects

# **Senior Software Engineer**

Sep 2018 - Apr 2021

Recovery Group

Recovery is a credit recovery company at Itaú Unibanco bank, focused on the management and recovery of overdue loans.

Member of the Digital Recovery Community, integrating the Digital Squad, working in multidisciplinary teams in the development of digital products

- Application development using .NET platform and Frameworks such as Angular and React
- Integration with digital channels using WebServices, WebApi's, Microservices, and monitoring with Application Insights.
- Deploying applications in high availability environments using Azure DevOps with CI / CD pipeline.

Software Engineer Mar 2018 - Sep 2018

Capgemini

Capgemini is a global multinational consulting, technology services and digital transformation company

Consulting in a government institution, working with systems focused on tax registration

- Application development using ASP.NET MVC (Javascript, CSS3, HTML5, Bootstrap, KnockoutJS, RequiredJS)
- Development of unit tests with MSTest and analysis and inspection using OpenCover and ReportGenerator.
- Client meetings with clients to understand their needs, requirements gathering, proposal preparation and timelines executions

# **Software Developer**

Sep 2015 - Mar 2018

Ernst & Young

Ernst & Young is a multinational professional services firm. It provides assurance (including financial audit), tax, consulting and advisory services to companies Working with process automation to assist audit processes

- Development of Web and Desktop applications in .NET to import processes and analysis of inconsistencies in files, to assist in auditor's decision making
- Creation of customized report templates dynamically generated based on customer needs with MS Reporting Services and MS Report Viewer

# **Software Developer**

May 2013 - Sep 2015

Coreon

Coreon is a Brazilian company that offers services in Consulting, Development of Customized Solutions, Integration and Outsourcing of Applications, in addition to specific products for the Insurance Market, Capitalization Companies, Clinics and Hospitals.

- Development of Web applications in .NET for ERP of Capitalization for payments calculations, sales, commissions, awards and buy-back of capitalization titles
- · Optimization of calculation algorithms and queries in databases with SQL Server

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science**

University Sao Judas (USJT), Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil

#### **LANGUAGES**

English – Intermediate French – Basic Portuguese – Native

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- · Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate
- · Microsoft Certified Trainer

# **SKILLS**

- C#, VB.NET, .NET Framework, .NET Core, MVC, MVVM, WCF, Web API
- HTML, CSS, TypeScript, Javascript, JQuery, Angular, React, Knockout, JSON, XML
- SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, PostgresSQL, Mongo, Elasticsearch
- Microservices, OOP, SOLID, CI / CD Tools
- Azure DevOps, GIT
- TDD, MSTest, NUnit, xUnit
- SCRUM, SAFe, XP